<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-05T13:49:31-05:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Journey Into Night</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Reissue of Anarchist Tension</title><link href="/2018/12/29/anarchist-tension.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reissue of Anarchist Tension" /><published>2018-12-29T20:44:47-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-29T20:44:47-05:00</updated><id>/2018/12/29/anarchist-tension</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/12/29/anarchist-tension.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;death-the-anarchic-and-ephemerality&quot;&gt;Death, the Anarchic and Ephemerality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modernism-and-static-worlds&quot;&gt;Modernism and Static Worlds&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of avoiding boredom we will be ignoring the liberals, with their pithy calls for reform and their constant droning on about moderation, content to sit around in moral certainty while the world burns.  Instead the focus here will be firmly placed on those that are more like us(anarchists), those that we sometimes call, although often with hesitation, our allies.  We will focus on the dynamic that allows those who consider themselves revolutionaries to engage in pointless activism, and elements of that activism that can inform our understandings and critiques of the radical project as it currently stands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The political space around us, bombards us with a constellation of ideas, concepts that form the foundations of the modernist political ethos and aesthetic. This constellation forms the political into a special, identifiable space, one filled with pageantry, from electoral rallies to the protest.  The activity undertaken in this space is framed around a tireless dedication, which pushes activists to the point of burnout or, in extreme situations, death.  Within this universe those who participate, who stand up to power in the very act of their speech, are glorified for their sacrifices.  A sacrifice that in the end will shift the political winds and change the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concepts and aesthetics can be seen in the standard imagery that appears on campaign fliers, from that of the candidate or figure head seemingly beloved by a large anonymous crowd, to the smoke filled streets that form the backdrop for those more militant. These are the images of activity motivated by symbolic moral outrage, reduced to spectacular displays and structured to serve symbolic goals.  Within this world, politics is reduced to a space in which glorious heroes fight monstrous systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the modernist concept of the political a conceptual universe comes to prominence, complete with grand narrative visions of the future and universal understandings of the present.  This zone of abstraction can take a wide variety of forms, from the platitudes of Leninism to the more complex, but no less abstract declarations of the Tiqqunists.  These frameworks depart from a series of assertions, with two bodies of assertion rising to immediate prominence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first of these bodies lay in the abstraction of the immediate plane of engagement.  Far from the tactical analysis found in military theory or the information driven operations of hacker spaces, the modernist political space is one in which the moment and the concept fuse into a singular entity. The moment becomes nothing more than a point in which some universal narrative becomes expressed or inscribed.  This is clear whenever we hear a so-called “radical theorist” speak on the correct strategy, discuss the ways in which certain forms of activity carry moral weight or articulate a need to raise consciousness.  Underlying this is an assertion that moments, in themselves, are not in any way different; history is nothing more than the expression of a dynamic that is general and explainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comes into contact with the second body, centered around the role of revolutionaries as agents of history.  Here we find the motivations that drive phenomena like suicide bombers or the glorified revolutionary martyr.  It is here that those who go to boring and repetitive marches can see themselves marching toward an utopian future, with the march serving as a symbol of conflict, and sacrifice, regardless of negotiations with the police.  It is the Nazareth where messiah complexes are born. Those that engage begin a process of separation, of defining themselves as political agents within political moments. This understanding is based on a grand perversion of the dynamics of revolutions past, which are never momentary, not based on identifiable figures and only rarely centered on those that identify themselves as revolutionaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These assertions then come to combine themselves with the concept of a future that is clear and definitive. The future articulated in modernist grand narratives is not one created through the conflict, but the emergence of a true state of existence from the smoldering rubble of the old world.  It takes on a religious tone, veering into the millenarian, in which action is not framed as that which generates the possibility of the future, and becomes an understanding of action in which conflict generates the end of itself, the stable, static, universal utopian future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These dynamics  construct a form of the political which becomes removed from itself.  The conflictual space opened by political engagement, the destruction of certainties that follows conflict with the police, the possibilities unleashed in everything from basic illegality to the riot, are all removed from themselves.  The entirety of the political is inserted into imaginary spaces in which everything becomes an expression of a narrative.  In this everything becomes symbolic; it is no wonder why revolutionaries in the modern age often repeat the same tactical choreography over and over, in the isolated planned conflict of the demonstration, migrating from one moral outrage to another without much impact on the actual functioning of the material operations of the state. A symbolic struggle within abstract spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modernism, in this sense, creates a dead barren space.  It is a space devoid of the complexities of life, the difficulties of tactical and material conflict, the possibilities of a future determined through our actions within the dynamics of other activity.  The world is replaced with a story, whose happy ever after has nothing to do with who we are or what we do. Not only dose this lead to political ineffectiveness but also the colonization of the political by a totalizing vision of the present and future that robs us of any agency. It is in this sense that modernism is a machine in which the world is always produced as a dead thing, an inert and understandable object, until the millenarian conflagration, at which point the determinist future is ushered into existence.  It is the politics of a death cult, of the religious order, of the grand historical fiction, and one that we must conspire to escape with everything we have, shooting backwards the whole way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental problem is that this line of flight, this route of escape is entirely uncharted. All past attempts have fallen into the same platitudes, such as the existentialists collapse into a politics of authenticity. Escape must mean to chart a route of egress defined not through its own limits, but through the destruction of limits; not through the embrace of new universal ideas, but through the destruction of universality, the concept of the utopian future and even the concepts of victory that populate the modernist imagination.  This line of flight will only emerge by embracing a new language and new forms of action, without singular meanings, but framed around multiplicities, paradoxes and tensions; a trajectory that does not see itself as an end, but as a point of departure, as a beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-anarchic-and-the-indiscernible&quot;&gt;The Anarchic and the Indiscernible&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of the revolutionary project lies a wager, one that is simultaneously simple and infinitely impossible to ever resolve in a way that provides satisfaction or peace of mind.  Within the concept of the revolutionary, or any concept that indicates the destruction of an understanding of social order, the question of how we exist in the world comes into focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existential implication is not merely an outcome of the question of the future, the sort of life one should live or want to live. It is of the resistant, the destruction of current forms of life, and the discourse around future moments that carries with it the entire weight of our understandings of ontological space, the ways that we understand existence.  This is abundantly clear within the trajectory of modernist political thought, in which the narrative of the past, the narrative of what existence is, constructs an understanding of the issues of the present moment and leads to the formation of the question of the future, a sort of eternal future in which life becomes joined with abstract thought.  It is on this point that the discussion within Anarchist Tension begins its engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of convergence between the moment and the concept functions as a point in which thought occurs, in which the act of thinking and the thinking of the act happen in parallel.  This convergence point is also the point in which a decision must be made, one of innumerable decisions that must be made within any given moment, but a decision that comes to form the condition of possibility for the others.  We have to decide, and this is going to sound odd, how we understand the concept of meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one understanding, the one that forms the foundation of the modernist understanding of the political, meaning becomes something that is, and that we can possess.  There are numerous formulations of this body of ideas, but they tend to center around an ontological understanding in which meaning and the understanding of meaning are grounded in universality; that there is universal meaning, and that life derives meaning from this universal meaning.  Within the traditional linguistic forms we would refer to this understanding of existence as the archic, as the positing of a world with necessary order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a comforting concept, one that posits the universe as understandable, knowable, stable and ultimately meaningful.  It is a framework in which we can sleep comfortably, with some semblance of certainty that the universe will not pull itself apart in the middle of the night, and that there may be some purpose to everything after all.  This understanding though, is a strange point from which to derive revolutionary ideas and activity.  By positing some essential meaning to everything, that there is some truth that can be known, that we can evaluate ideas in relation to, that we can ground our understandings of certainty within, we are also positing a universe of inevitability.  The world becomes predictable, and ultimately meaningless in relation to this ultimate truth that would have to continue in the same form, even in the face of the catastrophic destruction of the entirety of life and existence itself.  This is not only a universe in which the grand catastrophe is an ultimately irrelevant event, it is a universe that, along the same lines, renders the historical shifts latent in so many ideas of the destruction of prevalent forms of life similarly irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning can be understood in a different way, as something that is done, as an activity or something that is made.  In this understanding of the concept of meaning we have to think of the universe in a completely different way, not as something that is in itself meaningful, that provides or imposes meaning, but as something that is formed in moments.  This formation of the universe requires a shift away from traditional Western forms of thought.  Existence in this constellation ceases to be something that is an object that can be thought, both in the sense that existence is not a singular thing, and that existence is neither given nor stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we are coming into contact with here is nothing short of history, wholly separate from the Leninist concept of history as a coherent historical arc.  History in this sense begins to function as a circulation, a dynamic in which each and every moment that comes to be is simultaneously the convergence point of the entirety of everything that has ever occurred before, as well as a divergence from this trajectory.  The moment, the activity, begins to circulate in a space of possibility, the possibilities presented within the moment, and in turn comes to generate other dynamic possibilities in effect.  The moment becomes one of innumerable simultaneous moments, not in the sense of there being infinite universes, but in the sense that innumerable activities and events are all occurring, all of which impact the resonant effects of one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept of the universe is one that is much less comforting, it is one in which we must entertain the possibility of the end of existence at every moment. It is one that we cannot fundamentally understand through the conceptual generalities that populate thought.  Thought functions along the lines of static conceptual objects, symbolic objects that we name, and that through this naming bring into relationship with other objects.  If we understand existence as a grand ontological chance, as a dynamic space framed around action and effect, then the very form of thought becomes incapable of grasping, encompassing and inscribing itself onto and within these moments.  This is not only a universe of chance, it is a universe in which the very act of thinking exists as both one of these activities, but also at a fundamental separation from action itself, as a conceptual attempt of making sense, in vain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Bonnano argues, it is this understanding of existence that we can come to grasp life, not as an idea, but as a phenomena.  It is from here, from the anarchic that we can begin to think not only of the political, as this interchange of action and effect, but also of the relevance of the anarchist project, one grounded not in defined worlds and futures, clear ideas and truths, but in possibility itself.  This is not a concept of the anarchic that is based in building anarchy, constructing some defined future that can be termed anarchist.  It is not one that provides for the sanctity of the idea or the sanctuary of simplistic ideas of the world. It is one that forms around complexity, chance, risk, possibility and the dynamism of existence in itself, and in this a tension rises to the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-tension-of-speaking-of-the-anarchic&quot;&gt;The Tension of Speaking of the Anarchic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is from this position that we can begin to understand the concept of the anarchist tension. The tension not only of thought and activity, but of the concept if anarchism itself.  To grasp this tension it is important for us to begin with an injunction that is presented within the piece, to not separate thought from action.  If the analysis presented earlier is the case, and the anarchic is being understood as a space of possibility within a world in which truth is absent, and in which moments are generated through the dynamic interplay of activity, of life itself. Then the injunction cannot be to come to some true understanding of action as such, as if such a thing existed.  If this were the case then this would not be presented as a tension, but rather as an anarchist certainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One element of the initial layers of this concept of the anarchist tension lies in the rejection of modernism, and the ways in which this removes action from the particularity of the moments in which action occurs; this dead concept of life.  This element is a call to shift the point of departure away from the conceptual smoothness and simple explanations that can only come from absolutist understandings, and to embed oneself in life.  Within this element of the anarchist tension we come into contact with an understanding of life that functions to undermine the understanding of life. This functions to the degree that we recognize that life, in its complexities, and concepts, in their simplistic frameworks, are not something that can be reconciled, and that in the face of this unbridgeable chasm we choose to embrace complexity, and not subsume it to the concepts that we have about complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second element of the anarchist tension is the necessity of thought.  Within the traditional Western canon thought functions as a practice in which firm, clear, coherent concepts form the foundations of true understandings, departing from the Aristotelian tradition.  As we would have every good reason to not accept the patently absurd assertions underlying this arrogant understanding of thought, we then have to reconceive of thought itself. Not as a formation which exists in relation to truth value, but as a fluid process of making sense of things.  In this framing of the concept of thought the conceptual becomes nothing more, and nothing less, than the attempt to make sense of a world that we can never actually understand.  This is not a detriment; rather, in this formation of thought can become a constant process of becoming, a process of developing a constant re-evaluation of events as these events themselves develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final element, which both separates and reconciles these other elements of the anarchist tension, is the interplay of thought as an action and thought as conceptual exercise. In other words, the formation of thought itself can exist as what it is, an activity, one which, like other more overt actions, has effects.  We can see this in other thinkers, such as Sorel, in which thought itself becomes an act, one capable of overturning regimes, one which is measured, like any other act, through its effectiveness, as well as its power to motivate the insurgent project.  In this sense thought becomes both the foundation of the motivations of activity, as well as an activity itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The convergence of thought and action that Bonnano speaks about here is not about bringing thought and action into absolute alignment, which would undermine the entire anarchist project through the positing of a correct thought about action.  It is instead the convergence of thought and action that exists on the level of speed and fluidity; of reconceiving of thought as a constant process and action in itself, as well as the process of making sense of a world formed in activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in this concept of a closeness that we see a constellation come into focus.  The conceptual becomes that which we assemble to make sense of a constantly shifting terrain of activity.  The conceptual is also firmly constructed from a perspectival limitation, spatio-temporal embeddedness and historical positionality. The conceptual is tenuous and speculative, as well as the grounding that we have for the act itself.  The act then results from a conceptual calculus and comes to change the terrain, starting the process all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, rather than the contemporary American insurrectionist conceptualization, in which categories like the revolutionary subject and notions of desire come to form the grounding of action in itself, the only connection between the action and the concept become the relation to terrain itself. Both find a grounding in the immediate, rather than some sort of odd unity of thought and activity in a totalizing sense.  The expression of desire in the act, the assertion of existence in the moment, is not grounded in an abstract desire, or an abstract existence, some removed concept, but is rather firmly rooted in the notion of an immediate existence, an immediate concept of meaning, an immediate desire in this moment, in this immediacy, which Bonanno calls life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;down-with-modernist-projectuality&quot;&gt;Down with Modernist Projectuality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The questions raised by the anarchist tension are not questions that can be addressed in the traditional western form of discursive engagement; the positing of conceptually consistent universes.  In so much of conceptual discourse the game becomes whether one is able to answer the difficult question, overcome the challenge, outsmart the discursive adversary, at which point the adversary must submit to the inevitability of the correctness of a specific conclusion.  Not only is this  engagement the work of the cloistered niceties of academic spaces, but it is a discourse in which life never actually functions.  To escape the trappings of the narrative of correct conclusions, truth value, and the entire ontology implied therein, we  have to completely destroy intellectual meaninglessness, as well as run as far away, as fast as possible, from useless discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than the smooth, unstriated spaces of intellectual discourse and the arrogance of truth value, we have to embrace limitations, possibility, chaos and complication.  It is not only that we have to reject any conclusion that breathes fascism and fictional worlds in the same breath, we have to reject the questions that presume these conclusions at their point of origin.  This is not only a question of a new language, it is a question of realigning the totality of the ways that we understand the political.  This tension must remain a tension, an irresolvable dynamic without utopian eliminations.  It is the tension, the paradox, the contradiction that preserves the dynamic of construction and destruction that prevents the end of history, the state, from being imposed; it is the tension that leads to the destruction of modernist certainty, both conceptually and, if weaponized, in the materiality of existence as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overthrow of the modernist order is not something that could lead to predictable, easy to grasp and certain outcomes.  As in the destruction of any thing, including the past in the construction of the present, destruction always leads to possibility, and as such, is the very foundations of risk and uncertainty.  The very concept of certainty is the basis of the fascist order, a utopian ideal of a certain future grounded in smooth, atemporal concepts.  If we are to understand the world as something that we build, if we are to understand history as something that we construct through activity, then the very possibility of this activity occurs to the degree that comforting notions, like certainty and truth, are entirely abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of the anarchist tension is not important because it is “anarchist”, but due to the inherently anarchic ontology of tensions, of conflict, itself.  In departing from tension, from conflict, from the insurgent, it is not about resolving the conflict, but becomes how we prevent it from resolving.  It ceases to be about correct strategy, an approach which inherently removes the strategic from its immediacy, or about correct politics.  It becomes about the choosing of sides, of deciding whether one is going to attempt to realize the living death of the modernist end of history or reject it. That is, whether one will side with the state or fight, and after that, whether one will sit back and decide that we have reached utopia or perpetuate the conflict against utopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we abandon the concept of the movement, ideology, the necessity of political identity formed around concepts of the future, the need for such absurdities as agreement, programs and recruitment all become obsolete.  Without the weight of having to take power, of having to manifest a certain future, the question of whether we are popular, whether our ideas hold sway, ceases to matter.  If the tension exists between the reasons for the choice in the war and the materiality of the tactical situation, then the only question becomes one of destroying the state, eliminating the logistics of force, of burning the prison.  At that point it doesn’t matter whether our names go down in history, or whether anyone knows them at all; the task has been set in motion, in a process that never comes to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-full-text-including-new-supplementary-material-can-be-found-here&quot;&gt;The full text, including new supplementary material can be found here.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/the-anarchist-tension.pdf&quot;&gt;Anarchist Tension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Death, the Anarchic and Ephemerality Modernism and Static Worlds For the purposes of avoiding boredom we will be ignoring the liberals, with their pithy calls for reform and their constant droning on about moderation, content to sit around in moral certainty while the world burns. Instead the focus here will be firmly placed on those that are more like us(anarchists), those that we sometimes call, although often with hesitation, our allies. We will focus on the dynamic that allows those who consider themselves revolutionaries to engage in pointless activism, and elements of that activism that can inform our understandings and critiques of the radical project as it currently stands. The political space around us, bombards us with a constellation of ideas, concepts that form the foundations of the modernist political ethos and aesthetic. This constellation forms the political into a special, identifiable space, one filled with pageantry, from electoral rallies to the protest. The activity undertaken in this space is framed around a tireless dedication, which pushes activists to the point of burnout or, in extreme situations, death. Within this universe those who participate, who stand up to power in the very act of their speech, are glorified for their sacrifices. A sacrifice that in the end will shift the political winds and change the system. The concepts and aesthetics can be seen in the standard imagery that appears on campaign fliers, from that of the candidate or figure head seemingly beloved by a large anonymous crowd, to the smoke filled streets that form the backdrop for those more militant. These are the images of activity motivated by symbolic moral outrage, reduced to spectacular displays and structured to serve symbolic goals. Within this world, politics is reduced to a space in which glorious heroes fight monstrous systems.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/RAM.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Reissue of At Daggers Drawn</title><link href="/2018/12/28/at-daggers-drawn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reissue of At Daggers Drawn" /><published>2018-12-28T20:44:47-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-28T20:44:47-05:00</updated><id>/2018/12/28/at-daggers-drawn</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/12/28/at-daggers-drawn.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;thoughts-on-the-republication-of-a-uniquely-impactful-text&quot;&gt;Thoughts On The Republication of a Uniquely Impactful Text&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘How, under the present social order, do you reconcile the inhabitants’ desire to breathe with the interests of the bosses of the motor industry? Free circulation of individuals with the fears of the luxury boutique owners? Children’s play areas with the cement of the car parks, banks and shopping centres? The empty houses left in the hands of the speculators? The blocks of flats that look like army barracks, that look like schools, that look like hospitals, that look like asylums? To move one wall in this labyrinth of horrors would mean putting the whole scheme in question. The further we move away from a police-like view of the environment, the closer we get to clashing with the police’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;memories-from-a-long-time-ago&quot;&gt;Memories From A Long Time Ago&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin to discuss the implications of this piece, or the impacts of its initial translation and publication within the US context we have to go back to a time that few who are currently active can remember. This was an era in which the only forms of politics which were available to many came in the form of competing grand narratives of existence, and in which the forms of action that one could find emergent were inherently tied to a discourse of “the system” and “the movement”.  This was a time, around fifteen years ago, of grand movement activity, massive street marches, a sense of hope, but also a certain listlessness.  At the same time that it seemed that the streets were ripping themselves open, that the edifice of American hegemony was imploding from within, the avenues of possible activity were strangely closed, limited, absent of a pathway forward, an analysis of how power functions or the ways that contestation could move beyond the doldrums of the normal activist routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within this moment the perspectives of many that find themselves within the anarchist milieu were beginning a process of becoming.  While we watched the thousands march in the streets, often through a haze of exhaustion and delirium, there was always the sense that something was missing.  For some the causes of this absence became clear one clear day in April 2003 in Washington DC.  On this day many of us saw the police attack the anarchist bloc from behind, while still on the permit route, while the Communists from ANSWER fought us from  the front, attempting to prevent us from leaving the parade, while at the same time trying to prevent us from defending ourselves.  This all ended predictably, with broken windows, injuries, arrests and an array of “less than lethal” weapons fired in our general direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of us we got a glimpse into the causes of this absence on that day.  It was during the launching of the smoke bombs that it all became clear; we were caught between the imposed totality of the state and law on one side, and the equally authoritarian attempt to regulate the means of resistance on the other.  The gap between the liberals and the police that we ended up occupying that day was not merely a physical indication of being stuck between two enemies, it was the manifestation of something that we always knew, that the narratives of modernity, the grand political narratives that dominate the language of contestation, function to the degree that all opposition is eliminated. It was at this moment that many of us began to travel down a certain path, one in which the ends, and even the way points were unclear.  We began to attempt to understand the fallacies that we had all been convinced of, the failures of movementism, the naivety of liberalism, the reality that we are fighting a different fight, and the implications of this revelation.  On that day many of us decided that we were going to go it alone, to seek out what actual revolutionary action meant, and to break with the entirety of what we had come to expect in the context of so-called political activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To take on this task we needed terms, concepts, frameworks that could allow us to speak in a different language.  Not unlike Nietzsche, who set out to create a new language of thought, we were attempting to not only understand fighting differently, but to become different sorts of people in the struggle itself.  For as trite as it sounds certain texts came to exist in a space which allowed them to define this era for many of us, and At Daggers Drawn was one of these texts.  It was difficult to explain at the time what about the text gave it a certain aura, what allowed it to become an integral part of the lexicon and circulations of that milieu at that time; our ideas were still not very well formed.  But, over time, with the benefit of retrospect, what becomes clear on rereading this text, is not so much the tone, or the rhetorical bent that is important.  Rather, what is being presented here functions as a conceptual machine wholly different than many of the texts that we had access to at the time.  Unlike many of the texts of the time, which were attempting to still exist in a space of definitive speech and conclusions, while rejecting the idea of ideological certainty, this text seemingly rejected that very form of thought, not in declared rejection, but in the form of the argumentation itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What many of us saw in this text, and what enveloped many discussions around this text was less the sense that we learned anything, or obtained a different conclusion from which we could depart.  No, the enchantment of the text was that it posited this new language, not from affirming the legitimacy of the language, but in articulating a language simply through the rejection of other possible, more totalizing languages.  It was a text which undercut itself, challenged its own ability to speak for the readers, let alone the world, and firmly positioned itself as a howl, as a scream or an utterance; clearly enmeshed in its time and space, wholly of the writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since these days a lot has been lost; a whole generation has been scattered to the winds by repression, addiction, suicide and incarceration.  Increasingly it seems as if the monstrosities of movementism are on the rise again, while a small minority holds the line for liberatory concepts of insurgency.  As we watch the movement celebrities reassert themselves, complete with their platitudes around mass action, pacifism, and electoral compromise the question arises, when is it going to be time to break with the forces of modernity for good; when can we find ourselves in a position to not only defeat the enemies in blue, but also the ones that masquerade as radicals, complete with stylish hoodies and skinny jeans?  For us to ever find the ability to fight, to actually engage in the spaces in which we live, we have to embrace the inertia of that time, 15 years ago, when we decided that we were going to go out into the wilderness alone, regardless of the costs, impervious to the risks, comfortable with the sacrifices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;defeating-the-rotten-corpse-of-modernity&quot;&gt;Defeating the Rotten Corpse of Modernity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the contemporary narratives that underlie the majority of perspectives labeled as revolutionary there is a common existential structure, one which revolves around concepts of systems and singular solutions.  Within this conceptual space we are to imagine that the “system” is some sort of monolithic structure, which exerts an almost unchallenged ability to command the particularities of everyday life.  Outside of the superficialities of this sort of a narrative, and the ways in which it eliminates the complexities of the existential structure of what we loosely call capital and the state, this narrative has a  profound impact on the conceptual structures deployed in the attempt to think the activity of contestation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of this monolithic narrative, one which has a tendency to become more monolithic and absolutist the further one moves into authoritarianism, the structures of contestation take on a very specific form.  In the current day we tend to call these structures “movement”, or singular bodies meant to organize activity against singular systemic enemies.  Our activity is channeled into the bodies of these massive political bureaucracies, run by steering committees, often for the purpose of the gains of political opportunists.  We go to protests, hand out fliers, and go to meetings to determine what to do on the next day of action.  And, all this time, through the hours of work, the exhaustion, the fervor and the crush of street actions, we never are able to move engagement beyond the simple level of symbolism, the abstract discursive engagement with conceptual enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this contemporary moment, where the assertion of the primacy of unitary action through the medium of the social movement bureaucracy, combined with the insistence on pacifism, what we are left with is nothing more than a toothless form of contestation.  We are relegated to nothing more than the ritual of the march, the pagentry of the rally, and the inevitable discussion of the attendance at the event and how the “media” shortchanged the numbers.  We become locked in cycles, cyclical attempts to get more numbers to make a louder statement to get more numbers, all the while doing so in the attempt to be able to engage in a discussion with those that inevitably command the same forces of the state that we are in conflict with in the first place; at least revolutionaries would take parts of cities by force, sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems that are faced in the rotting edifice of the contemporary social movement cannot be reduced to questions of strategy.  This is not only a problem of a reliance on the ritual of resistance, or a question of the ineffectiveness of negotiating arrests with the police beforehand.  The problems here cannot be reduced simply to problems of the ways that we engage, the questions of armed struggle and the discourse around maneuver warfare.  The problem here is not merely that the Black Bloc has become nothing more than really militant activism, in all too many situations, or that we spend a lot of our time traveling from action to action to action, racking up little more than trauma and an increasingly sizable arrest record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core the problems here are not internal to the narrative that gives rise to the concept of the unitary social movement, the concept of the revolutionary Party and the focus on policy; all of this makes sense if we understand politics as functioning primarily through the lens of unitary structures imposing commands.  Just as with conspiracy theorists, who depart from a similar conceptual point of departure, or Leninists, who do nothing more than frame this point of departure in the language of pseudo-science, the effects are the same; the particularities of life are obscured, the ways in which capital and the state function are lost in their localities, and the very act of contestation occurs outside both the realities and complexities of our lives and the terrain in which conflict actually occurs within, the immediate.  To be able to transcend the limitations imposed by the superficiality of simple explanations and easy solutions it is necessary for us to begin to complicate the structure of the operation of capital and the state, to begin to rethink the terrain of functionality from the perspective of events and occurrences, rather than the assertion of the unity of systems; we need to move beyond politics grounded in a narrative centered on universalized, body-less monsters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to transcend these limitations, to be able to complicate both the narrative of causes, as well as the narrative of solutions, what is required is nothing short of a total laying waste to the structures that have grounded thought around contestation in the dominant modernist paradigm.  It is in the attempt to push a discussion that can finally push us beyond these limitations that Journey Into Night presents you with this pamphlet, and accompanying introduction outlining some of the themes contained within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;capital-the-state-and-everyday-life&quot;&gt;Capital, The State and Everyday Life&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The necessity of understanding contestation in the context of immediacy is not merely a broad existential point, but functions in the strategic space as well.  Within this text the entry point to this discussion begins with a discussion of the current state of things.  Rather than the dark presentations of exceptional circumstances, which we often see populating the frameworks of breathless radical screeds, this discussion begins at a widely divergent place; normality, boredom, suspension.  Far from the visions of slums and deadly factory conditions which populate so much of radical discourse in the early industrial period, we are facing a very different circumstance.  The context of capitalist operation is no longer located merely in the realm of policy, the imposition of private property and land enclosure, the forcing of the agrarian worker into the city.  Rather, the context now exists in the droning on of everyday life, the absence of dramatic change, maintenance and the management of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we are facing is a mechanism of capture.  Unlike some portrayals of the capitalist world, it is not that everything has ceased; this would lead to the collapse of the economy itself.  Capitalism functions in a much different way than, say, the Soviet state.  Rather than attempting to end all activity not proscribed by the state in a direct way the capitalist state functions more along the lines of canals, the process of framing action in the realm of economization and commodification, while utilizing the state merely for the purposes of maintaining the ability of the economy to function.  In this operational space the locality of power, the points of departure for activity and the logistical ability to act emanates from many sites, all facilitated by the functionality of the state, which exists to do nothing more than manage crisis.  In less obtuse language, the economy functions, companies rise and fall, jobs are gained and lost, and the role of the state is to do nothing more than to make sure that currency is supported, that subsidies flow to places that will facilitate economic growth and that the structure of private property continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of captured motion has effects that we can begin to see incredibly clearly in microscopic forms, neighborhoods are reduced to collections of commodified structures and consumer indexes in non-profit reports, as well as in the structure of macro-economic policy, the IMF measuring the economic success of a space based on median incomes and GDP.  The functionality of this framework is less in the imposition of force, as one would find in more traditional authoritarian spaces, but functions in subtle ways, in the construction of what we consider to be normal, in the very idea of the normal itself.  Not only does this reality of late capitalism require a reorientation, especially in the West, away from a radicalism based on resisting the extraordinary, that which exceeds the expectations of normality, as in attempts to resist wars,  but it also forces us to understand the functionality of what has traditionally been referred to as “the system”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, what the relationships which are prevalent in late capitalism make clear is that the modernist understanding of singular sources of power emanating from singular institutional sites is entirely insufficient to understand the functionalities of dominant paradigms in actual lived moments.  The “struggle” does not occur on the level of grand, epic street battles with the police, although this is always a part of resistance.  These struggles occur on the level in which the inscription of capitalist value and the logistics of the state actually operate, on the level of the moment, the level of the immediate, itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are the obvious examples that can be offered in order to contextualize this shift.  Of course capitalism functions to the degree that regular people go to work and use abstract resources accumulated through wage labor to perpetuate the consumer economy.  Of course the state functions to the degree that normal, average people comply with police orders, and every policy articulated by every politician is a police order.  But, less obviously the structure of conflict, the contingencies of moments and the contextualization of activity itself is where the terrain of conflict exists within.  The question is not whether the union organizer gets fired for being arrested during the riot, the question is why participating in the riot is unthinkable to begin with, the question os why electoralism is so pervasive, for example.  The terrain of conflict is not merely in the material avenues and barriers for action in a physical sense; but is also in the historical conditions, the material dynamics, of what shapes our thinking of the possible in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in this sense that the second turn in modernist notions of the grand revolution fail.  It is not just merely in the reductionistic misunderstanding of the terrain of conflict, but also in the impossible insistence on predicting outcomes, on developing the plan or the programme.  We here this insistence all the time, from the endless, useless debates about better future world to the random person in the coffee shop asking what we would do to replace prisons.  The insistence here is an absurd injunction to imagine, from a position in which our senses of normality and permissiveness are framed through categories that depart from the capitalist state, what a world in which all the categories that we use to make sense of things now no longer functioned would look like.  This calls us to not only achieve the impossible, to predict an incomprehensible future, but to do so in such a way as to limit the possibilities opened up by contestation in the first place, a concept that has been termed the end of history, or utopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is important about starting at the discourse around terrains of functionality is not merely to make a conceptual point.  Rather, it is from this point that we can begin to glimpse into both the problems of the failures of the modernistic revolutionary project, as well as to begin to see routes of escape.  The recognition of the microscopic functionalities of conflict and operationalization, we well as the absurdities of predicting future worlds allows us to depart from a fundamentally different space.  From this beginning point in immediacy the entire context for understanding contestation shifts from one based in the notion of the mass movement, grand revolution and end of history into one based in immediate action in localized space for the purposes of subterfuge, disruption and the construction of experimental possibilities; we move from the world historical grand project to the scheme planned in the basement, from a world of the utopian metaphysic to the materially graspable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;revolution-and-insurrection&quot;&gt;Revolution and Insurrection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reorientation of fighting and the logistical operation of power within the context of everyday life, and the particlarity of moments, comes to challenge not only the concept of abstract engagement with conceptually singular “systems”, but decenters the concept of contestation and resistance away its central location within modernity, the concept of revolution.  Much of modernist discourse, from the origins of the American and French revolutions all the way to the Arab Awakening movements and Occupy are located around the orbit of the concept of revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of revolution occupies a sort of peculiar space within the concept of modernity, specifically within the framework of liberal democracy.  As Schmitt articulates, the frameworks for engagement formed around liberal democracy are predicated on the assertion that discursive engagement, in rationally crafted spaces, supersedes all other forms of engagement; that the only legitimate form of political engagement is one that is fundamentally based on the rational discourse around ideas.  Now, this concept is based on an entire universe of assumptions around concepts of reason, the ability of particularized beings to understand absolute truth, the existence of absolute truth, and so on.  With these aside, and this is a topic for other essays, the totality of engagement within modernist discourses is based on the assertion of a political framework grounded in some concept of truth, with all political activity occurring as discursive attempts to change the superficial aesthetics of these forms, but not the form itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is from this basis that the concept of revolution emerges in order to address a problem and a paradox.  The simple problem centers around the concept of personal and subjective autonomy, the ability to make sense of the world in particularized ways.  \This raises the problem of errant state structure and action, or state action that departs from the concept of rational truth; or the problem of what occurs when the state form diverges, through the actions of the sovereign, from posited concepts of rational truth.  As stated in the Declaration of Independence, where this errant mobility is termed tyranny, the possibility of revolution emerges.  What is important here is that the concept of revolution is not an object that names a process of taking control, or a reclaiming of political autonomy; it only serves to name the mass action taken in order to reinstate concepts of absolute truth.  Beyond the Declaration of Independence, which uses revolution as an escape clause, we can also see similar rhetoric in both Leninist concepts of revolution, as well as theocratic concepts of revolution, which aim to return “society” to a state closer to a concept of truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From these roots we can begin to trace some elements of the concept of revolution that are latent in the framework itself, and which are not apparent from the outset.  The initial element that becomes clear is that the notion of revolution is ahistorical.  By this we mean to say that the concept of revolution exists outside of the particularities of time and space, and outside of the contingencies of activities taken within the material world.  As a concept grounded in a concept of absolute truth the notion of revolution functions as nothing more than a revelation, a coming of the inevitable end of history, the rapture, the Second Coming.  Revolution in other words eliminates the past, present and future in the inevitable, universal truth of the concept of the revolution itself.  It is a concept which is based in the assertion of the universality of its conclusion in all moments, before any events occur; the coming Communist utopia is always going to occur according to Lenin, the revolution is merely its harbinger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This initial ahistoricism leads to a secondary layer of elements, the debasing of the concept of activity from the immediacy of the operational logistics of power.  By decentering the concept of action from the immediate, by positiing it as the inevitable result of universal truth and by framing the enemy in abstractly systemic terms the concept of revolution removes activity from the immediacy of action, and begins to frame it in the context of both world historical inevitability and the notion of control over ground.  The question ceases to become what form the operations of power take in their immediacy, the tactical question, which becomes irrelevant once the concept of the state is understood as a systemic entity that can be declared divergent from the concept of truth.  The only goal, from this point of departure, then becomes the elimination of the “system”, rather than the prevention of local operation, the disruption of operation and the opening up of possibilities.  As such, revolution tends toward the concept of frontal warfare; even in Maoist concepts of guerrilla warfare the goal is always to take space, impose political systems and build to the point of frontal mass warfare against the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in this sense that we can say that revolution performs all of the fundamental tasks of any other modernist framework (generalization, ahistoricism, the elimination of particularity and the abstraction of operational dynamics into concepts of systems), but does so as a marker of the threshold.  In other words, even though the concept of revolution is fully based within the context of modernity, and serves to do nothing more than reframe modernity under different terms, it also exists as the limit of the discursive, the space where words break down into bullets.  As such, revolution is not the point in which the modernist concept of the state collapses, it is merely the last bastion of its salvation, the point before it breaks itself apart.  So, if the concept of grounded in a problematic point of departure, and replicates the same dynamics that remove us from the conditions of possibility of our own lives, the question is not merely what comes after revolution, but how do we destroy revolution in the act of exceeding its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This point of excess, the point of exceeding the concept of revolution, is being termed insurrection.  Insurrection here names a point in which one takes on the exceeding of the discursive assertions of the modernist project, while at the same time eliminating the baggage of the concept of universal truth, the notion of the utopian future, the abstract framework through which contestation is thought and recenters the concept of contestation in the immediacy of lived experience.  The insurrectionary project is not a positivist project, this is not an attempt to create the utopian future from the flawed present, this would be impossible to conceive of, let alone destructive and existentially nullifying to attempt.  The goal here is not to build the new world on some partial framework of understanding names truth.  Rather the attempt here is only to, through the mobilization of conflict, open up the possibilities of existence through the degradation of the operations of the logistics of control and regulation.  The concept of insurrection here names not only the elimination of the discursive assertions of modernity, but also marks the point beyond the last outpost of the modernist project, revolution itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not merely that the concept of revolution and insurrection are different temporally, in the sense that revolutions have longevity or something like this, as Badiou would have it.  Rather the concepts of revolution and insurrection are mutually exclusive, opposed concepts.  The notion of revolution, as understood in the modernist context, is grounded in the concept that rebellions against the present order function to bring about some future order, one laid out in the theories of the parties involved and grounded in the same existential assumptions as the structure being contested.  It is portrayed as a smooth process in which the conflict that destroys the present order somehow results in a clean transition to a future state.  The notion of insurrection functions in a completely different way.  Far from being grounded in the illusions of the determination of the future, and in direct opposition to the notion of social peace, the absence of political conflict, the notion of insurrection is a point of departure and condition of possibility. It function as a point through which additional questions can be asked, from the positionality of the impossibility, and recognition of the danger, latent in the attempt to determine some future world.  At the same time it functions as a term which names the possibility created in the destruction of imposed limitations.  As such, insurrection is not a political concept, as traditionally understood, but functions as a theoretical object which names nothing more than the possibilities present in moments and the unleashing of conflict to expand the possibilities of possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this sense insurrection, as an object, does not merely name the generally understood phenomena of street fighting, uprising, barricades and so on.  Rather, it names a litany of more mundane realities.  To the degree that we exist in a universe in which the entirety of events are not pre-determined existentially insurrection, or what we term the anarchic, is inherent in moments; things can occur based on the actions taken in these moments, possibilities always exist.  Beyond naming this simple existential state of affairs the term insurrection also names a positionality.  It names a decision in relation to the social war that we cannot escape; the social war imposed by the state’s attempt to eliminate these possibilities.  It is a position against, a position grounded in the attempt to degrade the ability of these limits to function in the present, in every present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;immediacy-and-the-existent&quot;&gt;Immediacy and the Existent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the transcendence of the limitations of the concept of revolution, and the recentering of the question of contestation around the immediacy of the moment and the materiality of the logistics of the operations of power the discussion can ground itself in the immediate, rather than the symbolic conceptual ether of the concept of the modernist revolutionary paradigm.  Immediacy here takes on a completely different structure than within the contemporary revolutionary paradigm.  Within this concept of the moment within the revolutionary paradigm the present functions in a dual role, as moment of analysis, where one merely analyzes the moment and begins to think through the process of building revolutionary capacity, and as a moment in which one builds the formations necessary to take power.  Within this paradigm the present becomes displaced; displaced into the ahistorical framework of analysis and displaced into some imagination of future events.  This approach, from the insurrectionary perspective, becomes a non-engagement, an attempt to think revolution without activity; an approach which fails to disrupt the state of things in favor of displacing conflict into some future moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within a perspective grounded in the immediacy of action and the moment the present takes on a fundamentally different tone.  Rather than a moment of pure analysis, the present becomes a moment of activity, a moment in which the possibilities that are present are leveraged in order to cause disruption, create conditions for disruption and the point of departure for active negations of limitations to the possibilities of the moment.  In this context tasks like analysis or writing become framed not as attempts to write the correct theory, imagine future worlds or build the Party, but become acts of disruption in themselves, measured purely based on their effectiveness, rather than their ability to reflect some concept of truth that we could never understand, if it exists at all.  The measure here is not on the level of victory, or the storming of the Winter Palace, phenomena that we cannot even imagine if we are honest with ourselves.  The measure is, rather, the ability of our activities here and now to both create possibilities in the following present moments, as well as to disrupt and degrade the functionality of the limitations that exist in the present.  Rather than an exercise in political fantasy, the practice of insurrection takes the anarchic as its point of departure in the attempt to expand the possibilities of the anarchic; both a strategic deployment of conflict as well as the objective of deploying conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question posed here is not one of how can ‘we’, framed as the grand revolutionary formation, combat the state on the terrain of open frontal warfare, as we would have it in the traditional revolutionary paradigm.  It is even less the question of the ‘movement’, the object that has taken the place of the Party in radical discourse.  The question here is not one of how we build the revolutionary unitary body, the singular entity that subsumes resistance to itself.  This is both fascistic and strategically absurd.  The question here is not one of moments we define as moments of ‘political’ action.  Rather, the question here is one of the immediate, the possibilities of the present, and the means deployed, alone and in small groups, to expand the possibilities of the next moments; the moments that follow this specific moment in time.  The question is one of grounding; the grounding of the question of activity back in the moments in which activity occurs, the present, the immediacy of time and space, here and now. Rather than building the context through which action becomes possible, the isolated world of the Party and the movement, the question being posed here is one of acting within the worlds that we find ourselves in within everyday life, within the mundanity of social war, the occupation of our neighborhoods by the police and the indignities of wage labor.  Above all, insurrectionary points of departure are a recognition that the state and capital are not abstract monsters that exist in power centers, but are constellations of actions taken in dispersed spaces, constantly constructing their existence in every moment.  Every moment, therefore, becomes a point of contestation, becomes a point in which this constant reconstruction could, and sometimes does, fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, and this cannot be underemphasized, the primary question being posed is not one that resolves itself in a solution; solutions are always fanciful.  The question being posed here is just that, a question.  Or, more accurately, the concept of insurrection, as a marker, marks the posing of questions without the possibility of the solution.  The solution, the end of history, the utopian moment or the revolutionary programme, posits nothing more and nothing less than the end of possibilities.  They posit the end of the ability to determine our present moments, the determination of the present through the vision of the future.  It is not only that this perspective has led to the revolutionary failures that we live in the midst of, or that they are glorified acts of Christian fiction, but that they posit a disturbing possibility, a world without possibility.  The question being posed here, the question of immediacy and activity, is a question because it marks not an end but a beginning point, a point of departure.  It is not that insurrection results in the glorious future, but it is that through insurrectionary activity, in the present, here and now, we steal back the possibility of the moment.  This is the only fight worth fighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This world is poisoning us and forcing us to carry out useless noxious activity; it imposes the need for money on us and deprives us of impassioned relationships. We are growing old among men and women without dreams, strangers in a reality which leaves no room for outbursts of generosity. We are not partisans of abnegation. It’s just that the best this society can offer us (a career, fame, a sudden win, ‘love’) simply doesn’t interest us. Giving orders disgusts us just as much as obedience. We are exploited like everyone else and want to put an end to exploitation right away. For us, revolt needs no other justification.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-full-text-including-new-supplementary-material-can-be-found-here&quot;&gt;The full text, including new supplementary material can be found here.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/at-daggers-drawn.pdf&quot;&gt;At Daggers Drawn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Thoughts On The Republication of a Uniquely Impactful Text ‘How, under the present social order, do you reconcile the inhabitants’ desire to breathe with the interests of the bosses of the motor industry? Free circulation of individuals with the fears of the luxury boutique owners? Children’s play areas with the cement of the car parks, banks and shopping centres? The empty houses left in the hands of the speculators? The blocks of flats that look like army barracks, that look like schools, that look like hospitals, that look like asylums? To move one wall in this labyrinth of horrors would mean putting the whole scheme in question. The further we move away from a police-like view of the environment, the closer we get to clashing with the police’ Memories From A Long Time Ago To begin to discuss the implications of this piece, or the impacts of its initial translation and publication within the US context we have to go back to a time that few who are currently active can remember. This was an era in which the only forms of politics which were available to many came in the form of competing grand narratives of existence, and in which the forms of action that one could find emergent were inherently tied to a discourse of “the system” and “the movement”. This was a time, around fifteen years ago, of grand movement activity, massive street marches, a sense of hope, but also a certain listlessness. At the same time that it seemed that the streets were ripping themselves open, that the edifice of American hegemony was imploding from within, the avenues of possible activity were strangely closed, limited, absent of a pathway forward, an analysis of how power functions or the ways that contestation could move beyond the doldrums of the normal activist routine.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/become_ungovernable.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction to Journey Into Night</title><link href="/2018/04/04/introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to Journey Into Night" /><published>2018-04-04T21:44:47-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-04T21:44:47-04:00</updated><id>/2018/04/04/introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/04/04/introduction.html">&lt;p&gt;The world as we know it is populated by spectres, spirits that haunt and possess the very body of the world.  These spectres, the concept of the nation, the idea of society and even the notion of the atomized individual, form not only the foundations of how we think about the world both present and future, but is also the basis of government force.  We are possessed with imaginary formations  that turn the very actualities of everyday life into nothing other than expressions of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to all aesthetic differences the concepts articulated by both the partisans of the contemporary order as well as those marching towards a glorious revolutionary future all exist within a framework that we will be terming the political imaginary. The political imaginary is that totalizing existential determinism that understands existence in its entirety and plans the future around that understanding. It is the conceptual ontology of political modernity,  a universe where we exist as little more than particular manifestations of truth.  This truth varies between narratives, from Christianity to dialectical materialism, but aesthetics aside, the consequences remain the same. Rather than a dynamic world, shaped by our actions and framed by the dynamics of history, we are being called to imagine a world that is smooth, rational and determined by truth. In an imaginary universe of truth, we become irrelevant, interchangeable vehicles of the manifestation of that truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In finding what lies beyond the quagmire of the totalistic concepts of existence and the political visions  that emanate therefrom we must articulate a position framed around the rejection of the imaginary ideal. So to start we must ask whether the definitive future, the concept of the planned utopia, the notion of truth itself, is either knowable and/or preferable in our discourses around the lives we live. It is with this understanding in mind that we launch this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an anarchist project but one that rejects the socialist concept of anarchism, leftism or any  attachment to a political tradition grounded in the narrative of an utopian future.  This is not a rebranding of traditional European socialism, we are leaving baggage of the 19th century Marxist milieu to LARPers with red banners.  We are anarchists and our anarchy is found in the possibilities opened by the subversion and destruction of capital and the state, rather than the attempt to engage in the political fiction of discourses of some future world.  Likewise, we are a definitively nihilist project; not because we have become hopeless, as in the vernacular understanding of the term, but because we understand that the opening up of the possibilities of the present only arises in negation of the political imaginary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than attaching this ourselves to universal narratives found in the international ideals of contemporary revolutionary thought, we localize, grounding ourselves in both the terrain in which we fight as well as a recognition of the limitations and arbitrariness of our visibility.  Ours is the terrestrial character of the partisan, if our fight is to be fought and won it must happen block by block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start our fight from a position of critique.  This is not because critique is a comfortable space from which to depart, but because it is the only task we find worth carrying out. This is not the critique of academia, staid, comfortable and polite, accessible only to those who can afford tuition. This is an active critique, for the active engagement with the immediacy of our lives, one not formed in order to redefine our existence, but one formed for the purpose of disrupting attempts at definition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not set out to form a new narrative, but to destroy the certainty of narratives and the concept of the world that result from positions of certainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, we are not attempting to define the revolutionary future, but attempting, through negation, critique and disruption, to open up the possibilities of a revolutionary present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite you to join us as we explore what it means to be in a world that is beyond the limits of the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The world as we know it is populated by spectres, spirits that haunt and possess the very body of the world. These spectres, the concept of the nation, the idea of society and even the notion of the atomized individual, form not only the foundations of how we think about the world both present and future, but is also the basis of government force. We are possessed with imaginary formations that turn the very actualities of everyday life into nothing other than expressions of ideas.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/intro.jpg" /></entry></feed>